Imagine yourself once again as a sales manager at Parch and Posey.
تخيل نفسك مرة أخرى كمدير مبيعات في Posh and Posey.
You've determined that another great way to expand revenue
وقد قررت أن هناك طريقة أخرى رائعة لزيادة الأرباح
is to sell new types of paper to existing customers.
وتتمثل في بيع أنواع جديدة من الورق للعملاء الحاليين.
In order to figure out the best prospects,
للتعرف على أفضل الاحتمالات،
you'd like to see existing customers whose orders omitted some type of paper.
تود أن ترى العملاء الحاليين الذين أغفلت طلباتهم بعض أنواع الورق.
Orders for different types of paper are marked in
يتم تمييز الطلبات الخاصة بأنواع الورق المختلفة
three separate columns in the Orders table.
في ثلاثة أعمدة منفصلة في جدول الأوامر.
So you'll need to write a query that makes logical comparisons on each of those columns.
لذلك ستحتاج إلى كتابة استعلام بإجراء مقارنات منطقية على كل من هذه الأعمدة.
You can see that most orders are for all three types of paper.
يمكنك أن ترى أن معظم الأوامر تخص جميع أنواع الورق الثلاثة.
Now let's start to build in the logic to find
لنبدأ الآن بإنشاء المنطق للعثور على
orders where one paper type might not have been ordered.
الأوامر التي ربما لم يتم طلب أحد أنواع الورق بها.
You can do that using OR.
يمكنك عمل ذلك باستخدام OR.
OR is a logical operator in SQL that allows you to
يعد OR أحد العوامل المنطقية في SQL والذي يتيح لك
select rows that satisfy either of two conditions.
تحديد الصفوف التي تستوفي أحد الشرطين.
It works similarly to AND which selects the rows that satisfy both of two conditions.
فهو يعمل بطريقة مماثلة لـ AND الذي يحدد الصفوف التي تفي بشرطين.
Let's build this out by first selecting
دعونا نبني هذا من خلال اختيار فقط الأوامر
only orders for which standard paper was not included.
التي لم يتم تضمين الورق القياسي بها.
You can see that this produces 825 results.
يمكنك أن ترى أن هذا ينتج 825 نتيجة.
Now let's add another paper type using OR.
والآن دعونا نضيف نوعًا آخر من الورق باستخدام OR.
You can see that this result set is larger than the previous one.
يمكنك أن ترى أن مجموعة النتائج هذه أكبر من السابقة.
That's because we've made this filter more inclusive.
ذلك لأننا جعلنا عامل التصفية هذا أكثر شمولية.
It will now return results where either one of
سيتم الآن إرجاع النتائج حيث يكون حل
these two logical statements resolves is true.
أحد هذين البيانين المنطقيين صحيحًا.
By adding one more logical statement,
بإضافة بيان منطقي واحد آخر،
we'll arrive at a query that returns all orders where some type of paper was omitted.
سنصل إلى استعلام يقوم بإرجاع كل الأوامر التي تم فيها حذف بعض أنواع الورق.